Stories have the power of captivating in a way that facts just cannot compete.
القصص لها قوة آسرة بطريقة لا يمكن للحقائق أن تنافسها.
When you're presenting your findings,
عندما تقدم نتائجك،
make sure to tell a story.
تأكد من سرد قصة.
When telling a story about data,
عندما تسرد قصة عن البيانات،
you should start with a compelling question.
يجب أن تبدأ بسؤال مُلحٍ.
If you're providing an entire presentation,
إذا كنت تقدم عرضًا تقديميًا كاملًا،
supplement your question with engaging visuals.
فقم بإكمال سؤالك باستخدام عناصر مرئية جذابة.
Continue to motivate your question with additional examples or
استمر في تعزيز سؤالك من خلال أمثلة إضافية أو
deeper questions to help your audience further
أسئلة أعمق لمساعدة جمهورك على التفاعل
engage and understand the context of your question.
وفهم سياق سؤالك بشكل أكبر.
Repetition of the problem is a good thing.
يعد تكرار المشكلة أمرًا جيدًا.
It can be simple and clearly explicit.
يمكن أن يكون بسيطًا وصريحًا بشكل واضح.
Repetition in visuals and audio cues
يساعد التكرار في الإشارات المرئية والصوتية
helps your audience move your question to long term memory.
جمهورك على نقل سؤالك إلى ذاكرة طويلة المدى.
Now, provide the data that supports an answer to the question.
الآن، قدم البيانات التي تدعم الإجابة على السؤال.
Highlight the answer so that no one can miss it.
قم بتمييز الإجابة بحيث لا يمكن لأحد أن يفوتها.
Conclude with a call to action for your audience.
اختتم بدعوة جمهورك للعمل.
Data by itself does not move people to take action.
البيانات في حد ذاتها لا تحرك الأشخاص لاتخاذ إجراءات.
You must motivate the action.
يجب أن تستحث الإجراء.
Data can assist in your conclusion,
يمكن أن تساعد البيانات في استنتاجك،
but you must provide the context for the next steps for your audience to take.
ولكن يجب عليك توفير السياق للخطوات التالية التي يجب على جمهورك اتخاذها.
In the next concept,
في المفهوم التالي،
you will see two versions of the same presentation with
سترى نسختين من نفس العرض التقديمي مع نفس
the same information and you can decide who tells a better story.
المعلومات ويمكنك أن تقرر من يسرد قصة أفضل.